<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Bitácora de Explorer: Gabriel Villagran</title>
    <link>https://gabrielvillagran.github.io/my_launchx_blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Bitácora de Explorer: Gabriel Villagran</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabrielvillagran.github.io/my_launchx_blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TCP Protocol and congestion control</title>
      <link>https://gabrielvillagran.github.io/my_launchx_blog/posts/post5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 12:00:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabrielvillagran.github.io/my_launchx_blog/posts/post5/</guid>
      <description>ns3-ai Computer Networking A top-Down Approach sicth edition, Kurose and Ross Transport Layer The internet&amp;rsquo;s transport layer transports application-layer messages between application endpoints. There are two transport protocols
 TCP UDP  For the study case of the example I will be focus mainly on TCP protocol.
  Reliable Data Transfer: Is when the protocol provides a guranteed data delivery service
  Loss-Tolerant Application: When a transport layer protocol doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide reliable data trasnfer, some of the data sent by the sending process may never arrive at the receiving process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NS3-AI</title>
      <link>https://gabrielvillagran.github.io/my_launchx_blog/posts/post3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 13:13:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabrielvillagran.github.io/my_launchx_blog/posts/post3/</guid>
      <description>Introduction
This project is being worked on by Jose Saul Castillo Ipiña and Gabriel Aldair Villagrán Saucedo for the Machine Learning course, under Dr. Juan Carlos Cuevas Tello and Dr. Pedro David Arjona Villicaña as advisor, our main goal is to understand how the simulator works and how we can implement the AI algorithms using the ns3-ai module. ns-3 is an open source simulator which is very helpful for research and educational use in networking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit Test with Jest</title>
      <link>https://gabrielvillagran.github.io/my_launchx_blog/posts/post4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 12:00:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabrielvillagran.github.io/my_launchx_blog/posts/post4/</guid>
      <description>What is Unit Testing?
Gabriel Villagran -a267572@alumnos.uaslp.mx-
Before I started to show you how to do this, let me talk about what is this and why is important to implement this tests to our projects.
Unit testing is a very useful technique that will help you to develop an application fully functional, Important: If you see a project without testing, be careful, all the projects must have tests and this one should fail and need to be passed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git &amp; Github</title>
      <link>https://gabrielvillagran.github.io/my_launchx_blog/posts/post2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabrielvillagran.github.io/my_launchx_blog/posts/post2/</guid>
      <description>Git and Github
Git and github are not the same, they are different things and are very useful if you are a developer, this useful tools are distributed version control tool that will help you to have your project safe, updated and if you are working in team this will help all the people in your team to collaborate and work very fast in the project.
Most of the open source projects are in github, so I&amp;rsquo;m 100% sure that the project that you are going to be part are going to be on github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Culture in software development</title>
      <link>https://gabrielvillagran.github.io/my_launchx_blog/posts/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:16:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gabrielvillagran.github.io/my_launchx_blog/posts/intro/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you about the values, feelings, emotions and what I personally admire in a developer.
We don&amp;rsquo;t have to follow the stereotypes, I personally think that not all the developers are serious, gamers, apathic and something like that&amp;hellip; We all are people and we have feelings, I like to say that the developers are a box full of surprise and you need to know them because the will teach you something.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
